Contact

Mobile: +387 62 321 205

E-mail: <u>almirmulahasanovic@outlook.com</u>

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/almir-mulahasanovic-482374a0

Address: Adija Mulabegovića 15

71000 Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina

Personal information

Date of Birth: March 18th1980

Gender: Male **Nationality:** Bosnian

Language: Bosnian, English (Advanced Level)

Technical Expertise

- Database development (T-SQL)
- .Net Dev (C#, WPF, Entity Framework)
- DAX (Data Analysis Expressions)
- Azure Data Platform (SQL Database, DW, Stream Analytics, Databricks, Data Lake, Data Factory)
- JavaScript / HTML / CSS

Technical Certifications





- Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Engineer Associate - Acclaim (youracclaim.com)
- MCSA: SQL 2016 Database Development -Certified 2020 - Acclaim (youracclaim.com)

Formal Education

School of Economics and Business - University of Sarajevo (September 1998 - December 2003)

My GitHub Repositories

- FIDAR Financial Data, Analyze and Reporting almirmulahasanovic/FidarProject (github.com)
- Demo Project IMDB datasets Azure Data Platform <u>almirmulahasanovic/ImdbDemoProject (github.com)</u>

ALMIR MULAHASANOVIĆ

Highlights

Specialist in developing and deploying profitability models and reporting frameworks in banking financial and business area.

Microsoft Certified Professional - MCSA in database development & Microsoft Certified Azure Data Engineer.

Driven by data management.

Passionate about Cloud Data Technologies and Services.

Long term experience in Business Intelligence Development and Financial Controlling.

Working experience

Addiko Bank

Addiko Bank Bosnia and Herzegovina

- Head of Finance Controlling Department
 Mar 2017 Present
- Integrity Data Expert Jan 2017 – Mar 2017



Raiffeisen Bank dd Bosnia and Herzegovina

- Senior Business Intelligence Analyst and Developer
 Jun 2010 Jan 2017
- Head of Cost Controlling Group at Raiffeisen Bank
 Jun 2008 Jun 2010
- Head of Acquiring Department at Raiffeisen Bank
 Apr 2005 Jun 2008
- Acquiring Officer at Raiffeisen Bank dd BH Jun 2003 – Apr 2005

Major achievement

FIDAR - Financial Data, Analyze and Reporting (Addiko Group AG Project)

FIDAR is profitability calculator. It's developed following banking financial standards for calculating profitability on different levels (segments, products, customers, branches). Implements Fund Transfer Pricing for calculating internal pricing and net interest margin on single deal, product and segment level.

Build as dimensional model allowing easy integration with different BI tools for aggregations, drill up/downs and ad-hoc queries.

User administration interface (dimension maintenance, batch processing, user management) integrated through Microsoft Excel using VSTO extension and MVVM model. Programmed by using C# programming language (Click Once deployment method). Business logic integrated and developed on server side (SQL Server). Project successfully deployed in 5 different countries of CEE region (Bosnia, Croatia, Serbia, Slovenia and Montenegro). Solution fully developed by me. Deployment supported by colleagues from 5 different countries in terms of Database administration and provisioning.